Mss.B.M58.1
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1816; 10X8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Warden, Gallatin, Correa de Serra, and Z. Collins.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Manigault Maringault?], Feb. 22-23, 1816; 8-1/2x7-3/4; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.L.S. 2p. Offers books for sale from Michaux.
  - Bill of lading of books to John Vaughan for the A.P.S., Jan. 27, 1817; 4-3/4x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 2p. In French.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 27, 1817; 10x8-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 694
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Lists people to whom gift of his work is to be made, among whom is Jefferson, the APS, Correa de Serra, etc. Forwards publications. Refers to Z. Collins.
  - Bill of lading to John Vaughan for the A.P.S., Feb. 1, 1817; 9-1/2X7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. and add. In French. Refers to C. Wistar.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 27, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Sends publications to the APS. Refers to Keating, Correa de Serra, and Wistar.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 3, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Introduces Collins. Forwards publications. Refers to Correa de Serra. Attached is a note dated 9 November 1818
  - Note to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 15, 1817; 6-3/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.N.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 10, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Business. Refers to Wistar, Bartram, and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 29, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 22, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter. Forwards publications.
  - Bill of lading of books for the APS sent to John Vaughan, June 27, 1817; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    D.S. 1p. end and add.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], July 19, 1817; 9-1/2X7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 697
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., end. In French. Forwards publications to the APS, Jefferson, etc. Business. Refers to Hassler and Warden.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], July 19, 1817; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 696
    Paris, A.L.S. 5p. In French. Asks for seeds from Carr and Bartram. Forwards publications for the APS. Jefferson and Hallser. Refers to Humboldt and Warden.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 5, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Forwards publications. Business. Refers to Humboldt and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1817; 10x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 2, 1817; 10x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Publications for Bowdoin College by B. Vaughan. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to his work.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 4, 1817; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    FILM 199 FRAME 698
    New York, L. 1p. and end. Asks payment due on Michaux's account. Endorsement pertaining to Jefferson.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 12, 1817; 10x7-1/2, 4-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 5p. and add., end. In French. Lists books sent to Bowdoin College.
  - Note to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 13, 1817; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    FILM 199 FRAME 699
    New York, N. 1p. and end. Thanks for payment on Michaux's and Jefferson's accounts.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1817; 10x8; Howe, Hezekiah, 1775-1838
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p., end. and add. Concerning Michaux's publication.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 16, 1817; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS, etc. Refers to Dr. James.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Jan. 27-28, 1817; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. Business for the APS., etc. Refers to Jefferson, B. Vaughan, and Correa de Serra.
  - Memoranda pertaining to Michaux's North American Sylva..., 1817-1819; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 3 items. Various sizes. The memoranda are dated from March 1817 to December 27, 1819.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1818; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications to the APS.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Jan. 23, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Duplicate. In French. Concerning the sale of his works to Belair. Attached to his letter from Belair to J. Vaughan; Aug. 5, 1818.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 3, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and 2p. bill of lading. In French. Concerning his publication, which is to be handled by Mathew Carey and Son.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Concerning publications for APS. Refers to Correa da Serra and Henri Gregoire.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 23, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and bill of landing. In French. Forwards publications to the APS. Introduces Himelÿ.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, March 7, 1818; 10x8; Belair, Lewis D.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p., end. and end. Orders Michaux's work on oaks.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 7, 1818; 10x7-3/4; Himely, John James
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications from Michaux.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for F. A. Michaux, March 9, 1818; 7x8; Belair, Lewis D.
    D. 1p., end.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 15, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
  - Bill of lading to J[o]hn Vaughan, June 15, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. and end. In French.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 20, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Wistar.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 27, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., add., end. APS business. Refers to Warden and Wistar.
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Carr, Philadelphia, July 1, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Purchase of plants. Will be paid by J. Vaughan. Refers to W. Bartram.
  - List of books from F[rançois] A[ndré] Michaux left with Thomas Dobson for sale, July 11, 1818; 8x5; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841.
    D. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 30, 1818; 9-1/2x8; Belair, Lewis D.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and enc. of 2p. Lists books for sale.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 5, 1818; 10x8; Belair, Lewis D.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Orders Michaux's works. Attached to letter from F. A. Michaux to J. Vaughan; Jan. 23, 1818.
  - Note to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 5, 1818; 6-1/4x7-3/4; Belair, Lewis D.
    New York, A.N.S 1p., end. Asks for copies of Michaux's work.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 19, 1818; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications for the APS from F. A. Michaux.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 19, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 700
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications to the APS, Jefferson, Maclure, Hassler and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1P. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Statement of periodicals sent to J[o]hn Vaughan for the A.P.S., Sept. 26, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 16, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Maclure.
  - Receipt to J[oh]n Vaughan for Michaux's works, Oct. 28, 1818; 3-3/4x6; Conrad, Solomon White, 1779-1831
    D. 1p.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p., end. and add. In French. Introduce Victor LeRoy. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Note to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 27, 1818; 5x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.N.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning publications.
  - Note to [Jacob] Bigelow, Boston, Dec. 12, 1818; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.N.S. 1p. In French. Presents his publication through John Vaughan. On Same sheet is note from Bigelow to J. Vaughan; April 6, 1819
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 9, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 701
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards his work to be presented to the APS, Jefferson and B. Vaughan. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Concerning publications for the APS. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 6, 1819; 10x8; Bigelow, Jacob, 1787-1879
    Boston, A.N.S. 1p. and add., end. Asks for Michaux publication. On same sheet as letter from Michaux to Bigelow; Dec. 12, 1818.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 8, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Concerning his work.
  - Note to [Thomas] Sully, April 27, 1819; 3-1/2x7-3/4; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.N.S. 1p. Copies of Michaux to be delivered to Conrad.
  - Note to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 30, 1819; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, N. 1p. and add., end. Sends bill of lading for books.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 19, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Concerning his work. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Bill of lading to John Vaughan of books for the APS, Oct. 17, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. and end. Attached to this are 2 other sheets pertaining to the same shipment. In English and French.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 17, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Maclure and Seybert.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 28, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Correa de Serra and Maclure.
  - Letter to [François André] Michaux, Paris, Nov. 19, 1819; 10x8; Institut royal de France. Classe d’histoire et de littérature ancienne
    Paris, A.L.S.: Dacier. 1p. and add.,end. In French. Thanks for APS publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 26, 1819; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Concerning publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 1820; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3P., add. and end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - List of publications forwarded to John Vaughan, March 23, 1820; 8x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 25, 1820; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Death of Palisot de Beauvois. Refers to Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 3, 1820; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. end. add. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Keating, Maclure, and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 24, 1820; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1P. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 12, 1821; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Forwards publications to the APS. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 21, 1823; 9-3/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 17, 1823; 10-1/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 15, 1824; 10-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Seal. Donates journals of A. Michaux. Cf. Minutes, p. 530. On same sheet is letter from APS to F. A. Michaux; May 21, 1824.
  - Letter to [François André Michaux], May 21, 1824; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    L.S.: Rob[ert] M. Patterson. 1p. Send by [Samuel] Brown. Thanks for A. Michaux journals. On same sheet as letter from F. A. Michaux to APS; Jan. 15, 1824.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 28, 1825; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, June 25, 1827; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add end. Publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, July 12, 1827; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p., add. and end. Lists publication to be shipped to the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1827; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Distributed volumes sent by the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 18, 1828; 8x10; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Introduces Henri Ternaux.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 5, 1828; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Delivered publications to Bertrand from the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 10, 1828; 10-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards Publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 24, 1828; 10-1/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1P. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Samuel Brown.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 1830; 10x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 19, 1830; 10x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Renewed journal subscriptions for the APS.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 27, 1830; 10-1/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. APS business. Refers to Samuel Brown.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Nov. 30, 1830; 10x8; Eyries Freres & Cie.
    Philadelphia, Havre, L. 1p. and add. In French. Forwarded package to Michaux and is sending package to the APS.
  - Letter to D[avid] B[ailie] Warden, Sept. 8-9, 1832; 12x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    L. 2p. Friendly letter. Concerning publications. On same sheet as letter from Vaughan to Michaux; Sept. 8, 1832.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 27, 1832; 10-1/4x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Illness of D. B. Warden. Cholera in Paris. Will leave legacy to the APS.
  - Letter to F[rancois] A[ndré] Michaux, Paris, Sept. 8, 1832; 12x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Copy. Business for APS. On same sheet is letter from J. Vaughan to Warden; Sept. 8-9, 1832.
  - List of books forwarded to the American Philosophical Society, Nov. 2, 1832; 9-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p., end. by John Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1832; 10-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1P. and add. Business. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 17, 1833; 10-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Concerning publications sent to the APS.
  - Bill drawn J[ohn] Vaughan of the American Philosophical Society, May 10, 1833; 3-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S 1p. and end. In French.
  - Note to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 4, 1834; 4-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.N.S. 1p. and end. Orders payment by the APS to Arthur Bertrand [which is done on the reverse of the note].
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical Society for publications purchased for D. B. Warden to be placed in F. A. Michaux hands, Aug. 13, 1834; 4-1/2x8; Dobson, Judah
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p. and end. by J. Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 17, 1836; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1P. and add., end. In French. APS Business.
  - Papers pertaining to legacy for the American Philosophical Society, Oct. 11, 1852; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    D.S. 6 items. Various sizes. In French. Contains several copies of his will. Also with this group is: T. Dunlap. Certification ...; Dec. 12, 1856.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Oct. 24, 1852; 11x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Vauréal, A.L.S. 4p., end.by C. B. T[rego]. In French. Will leave legacy to APS and Massachusetts society for agriculture, due to pleasant reception he and his father found in the U.S.
  - Letter to R[obert] M[askell] Patterson, Oct. 27, 1852; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. by C. B. T[rego]. Enc. Concerning F. A. Michaux's bequest. For enclosure, see: F. A. Michaux. Will; Sept. 4, 1855.
  - Pertaining to the Michaux legacy, ca. 1855; 7-3/4x5-1/4 and 7-1/2x6-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    D. 3p. and end. In French.
  - Will, Sept. 4 - Oct. 5, 1855; 8" x 12"; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Copy of D. 4p., end. In French. Copy once in possession of G. B. Wood. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949. Along with this is a wrapper endorsed in hand of G. B. Wood: "1862 Papers concerning affair of legacy of M. Michaux to the Am. Philos. Society June 17th." This enclosed 11 items concerning Dr. Wood's negotiations in re the Michaux legacy in 1862, presented by the College of Physicians - of. Donation book, Jan.6, 1949.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Sept. 15, 1856; 8x5-1/4; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning the death of F. A. Michaux and his bequest to the APS.
  - Report of committee on F. A. Michaux's testamentary writing, Oct. 17, 1856; 10-1/2x8-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: J. K. Kane, Geo[rge] Sharswood, and E. Durand. 1p. and end. Pertaining to the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Nov. 18, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Regarding memoir on F. A. Michaux.
  - Certification of authenticity of copy of François André Michaux's will, Dec. 12, 1856; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Dunlap, Thomas
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 1p. and end. Certification of authenticity of Machaux's will. In folder with: F. A. Michaux. Papers pertaining to legacy...; Oct.11, 1852.
  - Letter to de Bois-Branet, Pontoise, Dec. 17, 1856; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L. 2p. and end. and add. In French. Concerning F. A. Michaux's bequest to the APS.
  - Minutes, Sept. 19, 1856 - May 3, 1867; 9-3/4x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 6p. and end. Extracts. Pertaining to the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 6, 1857; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Germain, A., (Alexandre), 1809-1887
    Pontoise, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, March 17, 1857; 10x8; Fay, Richard Sullivan
    Boston, L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning the Michaux bequest to the Massachusetts Society for the Promotion of Agriculture.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, April 17, 1857; 10x8; Loring, Charles G. (Charles Greely), 1794-1867
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to A.Germain, Pontoise, April 22, 1857; 9-3/4x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. and end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy to the APS and the Massachusetts society. Refers to Asa Gray.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, Philadelphia, May 19, 1857; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Germain, A., (Alexandre), 1809-1887
    Pontoise, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Report of the committee recommending the acceptance of the Michaux legacy, July 17, 1857; 12-1/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Cha[rle]s B. Trego, J. K. Kane and E. Durand. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to John Penington and son, Philadelphia, Sept. 9, 1858; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Bossange, Hector, et fils
    Paris, L. 2p., end. In French. Wishes instructions from the APS as to the Michaux legacy. Enclosed originally in letter from Dunglison to Trego; Oct. 1, 1858.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Oct. 1, 1858; 7x4-1/2; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Encloses letter from Bossange to Penington pertaining to the Michaux Legacy. For enclosure, see: Bossange to Penington; Sept. 9, 1858.
  - Letter to Hector Bossange, Paris, Oct. 4, 1858; 12-1/2x8; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. with initials. 2p., end. Copy. Asks him to handle the Michaux legacy legal question for the APS.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Nov. 11, 1858; 11x8-1/2; Bossange, Hector
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, Philadelphia, Nov. 18, 1858; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bossange, Hector
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Needs power of attorney from the APS in order to collect the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Hector Bossange, Paris, Dec. 24, 1858; 6-1/2x8; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. and end. Copy. Business of collection the Michaux legacy for the APS.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Feb. 7, 1859; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bossange, Hector
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Expenses for collecting the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Asa Gray, Feb. 28, 1859; 7x7-3/4; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874